mashery.com 2018-06-23

# TIBCO Privacy Policy | TIBCO Software

TIBCO Software Inc. ("TIBCO" "we" or "us") is committed to protecting our users' privacy. We feel it is important that you fully understand the terms and conditions under which we use the information we gather from you, including through the use of our websites (“Sites”), hosted service offerings (“Services”) and mobile applications (“Mobile Apps”, and together with our Sites and Services, our “Offerings”). Please read this Privacy Policy ("Policy") carefully to understand how we will use and protect your personal information. A listing of Offerings to which this Policy specifically applies is available here. The Policy also describes the choices available to you regarding how you can access and update this information. Changes to this Policy will be announced on the home page of our Sites and Mobile Apps so please check back periodically.

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

TIBCO participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

TIBCO is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf in certain circumstances.  We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, TIBCO is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

TIBCO acknowledges that under Privacy Shield there exists a right to access your personal information. Please see our "Services" section below for further detail regarding access.

Pursuant to Article 37 of the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation, TIBCO has appointed a Data Protection Officer, Christoph M. Alberts. Mr. Alberts may be reached by email at [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com).

This Policy will explain the following regarding use of our Site:

  1. What information do we collect from you?
  2. With whom do we share your information?
  3. How may you update, correct, or delete your Personal Information?
  4. What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?
  5. "Cookies" and other Tracking Technologies
  6. Children, Parental Consent, and Privacy
  7. You should carefully review privacy policies of any third party sites accessible from our Site.
  8. Contacting us about privacy questions or concerns
  9. Privacy Policy changes

## 1\. What information do we collect from you?

In order to better provide you with services, we collect two types of information about its visitors: Personal Information and Non-Personal Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth and efficient experience while using our Offerings.

### Personal Information

Personal Information refers to the specifics of who you are, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address and any other information needed to provide a service to you while using our Offerings. We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected information with other information we collect about you to improve services, marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

When you download and use our Mobile Apps, we automatically collect information regarding your device system and performance information, such as operating system version, operation system type, hardware usage statistics, and app version. We may also access the device file storage for photos, microphone, camera, and contacts. You can opt out of this at the device level.

TIBCO collects Personal Information when you register with TIBCO for a TIBCO account as a customer, potential customer, or guest user, when you use certain TIBCO products or services, when you register to attend a seminar or participate in an online forum, blog, or a voluntary survey, when you ask to be included in an email or other mailing list (see "Choice/Opt-Out" below), when you submit an entry for promotions, or when you submit your Personal Information to TIBCO for any other reason. We use the Personal Information that we collect to send you information that you have requested, respond to an inquiry, or to facilitate the features in our Offerings as described in this Policy. From time to time, TIBCO receives Personal Information from business partners and vendors. TIBCO only uses such information if it has been collected in accordance with acceptable privacy practices consistent with this Policy.

When using our Mobile Apps, we will provide you the option to add your location in conjunction with some features of the Mobile App such as adding your location to a post. We ask you to opt into providing us with your geo-location data each time you provide it. If you no longer wish to allow us to track your geo-location information in the Mobile App, you may turn this off at the device level.

### Services

TIBCO collects information on behalf of our Clients and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it possesses. The use of this data will be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which our Clients have engaged TIBCO. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by them, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer Personal Information to companies that help us provide our services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients. We acknowledge that you have the right to access your personal information. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would like to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, direct your inquiry to our Client (the data controller). If the Client requests TIBCO to remove the data, we will respond to that request in 30 days. TIBCO will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Clients. TIBCO will also retain this Personal Information as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Social Media Widgets

Our Sites include Social Media Features or interactive mini-programs. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Sites, and may set a cookie to enable the Features to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Blogs & Testimonials

If you comment on the blog, you should be aware that any Personal Information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of the blog, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the Personal Information you choose to submit in the blog. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [tibcommunity@tibco.com](mailto:tibcommunity@tibco.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

We display personal testimonials and other endorsements of satisfied customers on our Sites. With your consent, we may post your testimonials along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com).

Access to certain TIBCO Offerings require a login and a password. The use of those Offerings, and the information or programs downloadable from those Sites, may be governed by a written agreement between your employer and TIBCO. Unless you request deletion of your Personal Information as specified below, your Personal Information may be retained by TIBCO to verify compliance with the agreement, log software licenses granted, to track software downloaded from those pages, or track usage of other applications available on those pages.

### Referral Services

If you choose to use our referral service to tell your contacts about our Offerings or invite a colleague into your network, we will ask you for your contact's name and email address. We will automatically send your contact a one-time email inviting him or her to visit us. TIBCO does not store this information and uses it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

### Single Sign-On

You can log into our Sites using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you with the option to share with us certain personal information, such as your name and email address, to pre-populate our sign-up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information to your social media profile page to share with others within your network about your activities on our Sites.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Non-Personal Information: Non-Personal Information refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We gather certain information about you based upon the pages that you access in our offerings using various tracking technologies. This information is compiled and analyzed on both a non-aggregated and an aggregated basis. (See "Cookies" section below)

### Communications

#### Special Offers and Updates

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see "Choice and Opt-out."

#### Newsletters

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, visiting the TIBCO Subscription Management Center at <http://marketo.tibco.com/subscription-management-center.html>, or by or by emailing us at [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com). If you contact us by e-mail, we will respond to your request within 30 days.

#### Push Notifications

When you sign up to use our Mobile Apps, we will ask you if you wish to receive push notifications which we use to keep you updated on the activity that occurs within the Mobile App. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

#### Service-Related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. Please see "Choice and Opt-out."

#### Customer Service

Based upon the Personal Information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

## 2\. With whom do we share your information?

Because TIBCO is a global company, your Personal Information may be shared with other TIBCO offices or subsidiaries around the world to provide the services that you have requested. All such entities are governed by this Privacy Policy or are bound by the appropriate confidentiality and data transfer agreements.

TIBCO will share your personal information with third parties only in ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties. Your personal information is never shared outside TIBCO without your permission, except under conditions explained below. Inside TIBCO, data is stored in controlled servers with limited access. Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country where TIBCO, its subsidiaries, affiliates, or agents are located.

TIBCO may send your Personal Information to other companies or people under any of the following circumstances: when we have your consent to share the information; we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of TIBCO to provide a product or service to you such as a marketing partner, mapping service provider or Web analytics company (we will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose); or we want to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you'd like to hear about either from us or from our business partners. We will also disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law, to enforce our Terms of Use, or in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public or our offerings. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Offerings. If TIBCO is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Offerings of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your Personal Information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.

#### Newsletters

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [privacy@tibco.com.](mailto:privacy@tibco.com)

#### Push Notifications

If you wish to no longer receive the push notifications you have opted into, you may turn them off at the device level.

#### Advertising

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on our Sites or to manage our advertising on other sites. These parties may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on our Sites and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if you are located in the European Union, [click here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## 3\. How may you update, correct, or delete your Personal Information?

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your Personal Information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, or delete/remove it by emailing us at [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

## 4\. What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?

We employ industry-recognized information technology to protect the security of the information you submit to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. The importance of security for all Personal Information associated with our users is of utmost concern to us. Our secure servers protect this information using password protection and advanced encryption, and we may use firewall technology for additional protection. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number, login information for our Services, or Geo-Location information) on our Offerings, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Furthermore, all of the user data we collect is protected against unauthorized access by physical security means.

We also encourage our partners and service providers to adopt and follow stringent consumer privacy policies. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Offerings, you can contact us at [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com).

## 5\. "Cookies" and other Tracking Technologies

We use cookies for the limited purposes of enhancing your visit to our Offerings and to enable us to track and target the interests of our users. A cookie cannot be read by a website or mobile application other than the one that set the cookie. No other company will have access to our cookies. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive or device, pass on a computer virus, or capture your email address. Our cookies are not tied to Personal Information.

Most browsers and devices are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser to notify you when you have received a cookie, or alternatively, to refuse to accept cookies. It is important to note that you may not be able to use certain features on our Site if you choose not to accept cookies. Some of the third party web-monitoring providers use cookies and other tracking technologies on our Sites.

TIBCO and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, ascertain your interest in our communications, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

### Mobile Analytics

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.

## 6\. Children, Parental Consent, and Privacy

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act took effect on April 21, 2000, and imposes certain requirements on Web sites directed toward children under the age of 13 that collect information on those children, or on Web sites that know they are collecting Personal Information on children under the age of 13. Our Offerings are not directed toward children under age 13. We do not knowingly collect information from anyone under age 13. If we find out that we have collected information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information immediately.

## 7\. You should carefully review privacy policies of any third party sites accessible from our Sites

Other sites accessible through our Sites have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each site's privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Please be aware that our Sites may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. This Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of those Web sites linked to our Sites. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit Personal Information. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these sites directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

## 8\. Contacting us about privacy questions or concerns

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of our offerings, or your dealings with our offerings, please contact us by sending an email to [privacy@tibco.com](mailto:privacy@tibco.com) or you can write to us at:

TIBCO Software Inc.  
Attention: Legal Department/Privacy Committee  
3303 Hillview Avenue  
Palo Alto, CA 94304

## 9\. Privacy Policy changes

This Privacy Policy was last changed on June 22, 2018. If we make changes to any terms or conditions of the Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted in this document so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. Any change, modification, addition, or removal of portions of this Policy that are changes in a material way will be announced on the homepage(s) of our Offerings prior to the change becoming effective. Please be sure to check this page before proceeding to use our Offerings.
